Dinesh Reddy
Deployed chef for configuration management infrastructure - Cisco
Bangalore

Bengaluru, Karnataka - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Dinesh-Reddy/139711455c45e1ad

To give my best in my professional pursuit for overall benefit and growth of the company that ${\tt I}$ serve by facing the challenges. I will show my caliber and gain some experience.

Professional Credentials and Abilities

- Having 3.5+ years of experience as a Build and Release Engineer in automating, building, releasing of code from one environment to other environment and deploying to servers.
- Extensively worked on Jenkins for continuous integration and for End to End automation for all build and deployments.
- ullet Having In-depth understanding of the principles and best practices of Software Configuration
- Extensive experience using MAVEN and ANT as build tools for the building of deployable artifacts (jar, war & tar) from source code.
- Build, Configure, Manage and Coordinate all Build and Release Management activities.
- Worked on Automated build & Release process.
- · Automated highly build, test, and reporting mechanisms.
- Worked on server machines with platforms like windows64, windows32 and linux64 to test and resolve the new release for group build issues, test failures, build breaks, Integration issues, and analyzed test logs in Agile Environment.
- Troubleshooting and problem solving of Linux/UNIX servers, debugging OS failure.
- Experience in working on source control tools like SVN and GIT.
- Expert in deploying the code through web application servers like Apache, Tomcat.
- \bullet Extensive experience of working with the release and deployment of large scale Java/J2EEWeb applications.
- ${}^{\bullet}$ Experience in Deploying to and administering in the use of Tomcat, Nexus, Apache web server, SVN.
- Excellent communicative, interpersonal, intuitive, analysis and leadership skills with ability to work efficiently in both independent and team work environments.

Willing to relocate to: Bengaluru, Karnataka - anywhere

https://www.indeed.com/r/Dinesh-Reddy/139711455c45e1ad?isid=rex-download&ikw=download-top&co=IN

WORK EXPERIENCE

Deployed chef for configuration management infrastructure

Cisco Bangalore - Bengaluru, Karnataka -

September 2016 to Present

Role: Build & release.

Environment: Java 1.7, Subversion 1.8, Ant 1.9.4, GIT 2.1, Puppet, Jira 6.3, Nexus, Shell scripting,

web logic 11g and Tomcat Servers 8.

Responsibilities:

 \bullet Coordinate with the Development, Database Administration, QA, and IT Operations teams to

ensure there are no resource conflicts.

• Installed and configured Jenkins for Automating build, deployments and test execution and

providing a complete automation solution using jenkins.

• Deployed chef for configuration management infrastructure, Implemented auto environment

creation using chef.

 \bullet Designing and implementing fully automated server build, management, monitoring and

deployment solutions spanning multiple platforms, tools and technologies including Jenkins

Nodes/Agents, SSH, deployment and testing.

- Created repositories according the structure required with branches, tags and trunks.
- \bullet Responsible for maintaining Multiple DevOps tools & configuring across all projects Subversion

(SVN), GIT, Maven, Jenkins, ANT, Artifactory, Chef.

- Configured application servers (WebLogic) to deploy the code.
- Experience in deploying applications on Tomcat and Web logic servers.
- Managed and document all post deployment issues utilizing the Post Deployments Issue Log.

Declaration

I hereby declare that the statements made herein are true, complete and correct to the best of

my knowledge and belief. I have not suppressed any material fact or factual information herein.

Place: Bangalore

Date:

software engineer

cisco -

June 2014 to Present

build & release engineer

Devops Engineer

Cisco Bangalore - Bengaluru, Karnataka -

2014 to Present

Technical Skills

Devops pipelines: Cloud bees Enterprise Jenkins, GIT, Docker, AWS

SCM Tools: SVN, GIT.

Continuous Build: ANT, Maven

Artifact Repository: Sontype Nexus Containers: Docker, AWS Basics, Chef

Static code Analysis: Sonarqube Check style CI Tools: Cloud bees Enterprise Jenkins.

Editors and IDEs: Eclipse (IMS Distribution), Notepad++ Operating Systems: MS Windows XP/2000/NT/98, UNIX, Linux

Database: MY SQL.

Servers: Apache, Tomcat

Tools: MS Office

software engineer

cisco

Build & Release through complete automation using jenkins and config by chef in complete cloud enviornment like AWS GCP $\,$

EDUCATION

BSC

Sri Venkateswara university tirupati - Tirupati, Andhra Pradesh

2012

SKILLS

AWS Devops

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Git maven jenkins vagrant docker nagios sonarcube chef ansible